Guide to the Local No. 35 of the Federation of University Employees Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Local No. 35 of the Federation of University Employees records
1941-1981
RU 488
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.27
(7 boxes, 1 folio folder)
The records consist of correspondence, lists, circulars, flyers, photographs, news releases, scrapbooks, an audiotape, and memoranda documenting the operations and activities of the Yale University Federation of University Employees Local No. 35, AFL-CIO at Yale University.
Federation of University Employees
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 36 (YRG 36), Records of Yale labor organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
These records contain correspondence, reports, circulars, news releases, photographs, scrapbook and a tape recording of union activities from 1941 to 1965. The Yale blue collar workers were organized by the United Construction Workers, United Mine Workers of America, Yale University Employees, Local 142 and chartered 1941 Oct 17. In 1942 February a contract was signed. A drive was organized for dining-hall employees during the fall of 1942. Edward J. Logue [See also Ms 959, Edward Logue Papers] was an active organizer in the union until he left for the war in 1942. During 1947 the union tried to interest library workers in the union. In 1951 the union for Yale employees became the Federation of University Employees, Local 1 and Local 35, Federation of University Employees, Hotel and Restaurant Employees AFL-CIO affiliated in 1956.
[See also YRG 47-E Yale Student Essays Collection, "Unionism at Yale" by John Larkin '54]
Industrial relations; Labor disputes; Labor unions; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Labor unions; Audiotapes; Federation of University Employees; Yale University -- Employees
- Federation of University Employees Local 35, AFL-CIO; Predecessors, circa 1941- 1965; Accession 19ND-A-153
  - Office files, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Office files, 1942? (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Labor's Non-Partisan League of Connecticut, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Office files, 1943 January-July-1953, 1956-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7-16)
  - News Releases, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Circulars, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Writings, Circa 1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Speech, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Federation Bulletin (incomplete), 1952-1963 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Manual "First Annual Summer School" Connecticut State Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Reprint "Labor's Public Responsibility in Internal Union Affairs" Labor Management Institute, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pamphlets and miscellaneous papers (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Yale Daily News (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Slide negatives (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1 tape recording (Box 2)
  - 1 UCW button (Box 2)
  - Oversize photograph of sixth annual outing, 1946
    General
    Item is a rolled photograph out for conservation.
  - Scrapbook (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "On Strike" signs (2), undated (Box AF3)
- Materials concerning employee union drives at Yale, 1946-1981; Accession 19ND-A-155
  Scope and Contents
  The records are divided into 3 parts. Part I consists of mimeographed flyers from the United Office and Professional Workers of America Union who were trying to organize a union within the University Libraries during 1946 and 1947. Part II contains Yale Non-Faculty Action Committee (YNFAC) flyers and newsletters and University memos regarding the union. This union was actively recruiting library workers from 1969 through 1972. Part III is made up of flyers from the Yale Employees Society (YES), Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU), Technical, Office, Professional (TOP) and United Auto Workers (UAW) Local 1701, together with University memos about University policy regarding unions.
  - Part I. United Office & Professional Workers of America, 1946-1947
    - Organization committee minor publications, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Part II. Yale Non-Faculty Action Committee (YNFAC), 1969-1972
    - Yale memos to the staff re the union, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Circulars from YNFAC, 1969-1972. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Oversize circulars & flyers, see Box 2
    - YNFAC Newsletter, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Yale Break, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Circulars & flyers, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Part III. Yale Employees Society (YES); Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU); and Technical, Office, Professional (TOP) United Auto Workers (UAW) Local 1701, 1975-1981
    - Union flyers and University memos, 1975-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
    - YES Newsletter, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 2)